National Civic Federation Pamphlets 5474
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Civic Federation Pamphlets
1908-1991
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Civic Federation
5474
0.33 cubic feet
0.3 linear ft.
Reports, pamphlets, publications.
Publications of the National Civic Federation.
5652959
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, April 07, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 03, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5650 mf: National Civic Federation Howell-Barkley Bill Correspondence on Microfilm
Biographical / Historical
The National Civic Federation (NCF) was an American economic organization founded in 1900 which brought together chosen representatives of big business and organized labor, as well as consumer advocates in an attempt to ameliorate labor disputes. It favored moderate progressive reform and sought to resolve disputes arising between industry and organized labor.
National Civic Federation
5652959
- Report and Explanatory Statement Upon Tentative Draft Workmen's Compensation Bill for Uniform State Legislation, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Prepared by Legal Committee, Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and their Prevention. To be discussed at meeting of Compensation Department Thursday, December 22, 1910
  - Item 1: Unbinding the Eyes of Justice, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: William J. Moran
    Notes: Paper read before the National Civic Federation, December 15, 1908
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: Report and Explanatory Statement Upon Tentative Draft Workmen's Compensation Bill for Uniform State Legislation, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Legal Committee
    Notes: Prepared by Legal Committee, Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and their Prevention. To be discussed at meeting of Compensation Department Thursday, December 22, 1910
  - Item 3: Memorandum Relative to the Respective Advantages and Disadvantages of Various Forms of Compensation Law, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Before the Congressional Employers' Liability and Workmen's Compensation Commission
  - Item 4: Draft of an Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: A Memorial Requesting the Recommendation of..., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Louis R. Schram
    Notes: Submitted to the Congressional Employers' Liability and Workmen's Compensation Commission
  - Item 6: Compliments of the Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and Their Prevention, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Legal Committee on Compensation
  - Item 7: Memorandum against the adoption of the the so-called Elective Compensation Plan, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Willliam J. Moran
- Memorandum Relative to the Respective Advantages and Disadvantages of Various Forms of Compensation Law, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Before the Congressional Employers' Liability and Workmen's Compensation Commission
  - Item 1: Unbinding the Eyes of Justice, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Report and Explanatory Statement Upon Tentative Draft Workmen's Compensation Bill for Uniform State Legislation, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Memorandum Relative to the Respective Advantages and Disadvantages of Various Forms of Compensation Law, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Draft of an Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: A Memorial Requesting the Recommendation of..., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Compliments of the Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and Their Prevention, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Memorandum against the adoption of the the so-called Elective Compensation Plan, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Draft of an Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Unbinding the Eyes of Justice, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Report and Explanatory Statement Upon Tentative Draft Workmen's Compensation Bill for Uniform State Legislation, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Memorandum Relative to the Respective Advantages and Disadvantages of Various Forms of Compensation Law, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Draft of an Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: A Memorial Requesting the Recommendation of..., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Compliments of the Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and Their Prevention, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Memorandum against the adoption of the the so-called Elective Compensation Plan, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A Memorial Requesting the Recommendation of..., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Submitted to the Congressional Employers' Liability and Workmen's Compensation Commission
  - Item 1: Unbinding the Eyes of Justice, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Report and Explanatory Statement Upon Tentative Draft Workmen's Compensation Bill for Uniform State Legislation, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Memorandum Relative to the Respective Advantages and Disadvantages of Various Forms of Compensation Law, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Draft of an Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: A Memorial Requesting the Recommendation of..., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Compliments of the Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and Their Prevention, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Memorandum against the adoption of the the so-called Elective Compensation Plan, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Compliments of the Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and Their Prevention, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Unbinding the Eyes of Justice, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Report and Explanatory Statement Upon Tentative Draft Workmen's Compensation Bill for Uniform State Legislation, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Memorandum Relative to the Respective Advantages and Disadvantages of Various Forms of Compensation Law, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Draft of an Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: A Memorial Requesting the Recommendation of..., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Compliments of the Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and Their Prevention, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Memorandum against the adoption of the the so-called Elective Compensation Plan, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Memorandum against the adoption of the the so-called Elective Compensation Plan, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Unbinding the Eyes of Justice, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Report and Explanatory Statement Upon Tentative Draft Workmen's Compensation Bill for Uniform State Legislation, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Memorandum Relative to the Respective Advantages and Disadvantages of Various Forms of Compensation Law, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Draft of an Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: A Memorial Requesting the Recommendation of..., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Compliments of the Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and Their Prevention, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Memorandum against the adoption of the the so-called Elective Compensation Plan, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Unbinding the Eyes of Justice, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Paper read before the National Civic Federation, December 15, 1908
  - Item 1: Unbinding the Eyes of Justice, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Report and Explanatory Statement Upon Tentative Draft Workmen's Compensation Bill for Uniform State Legislation, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Memorandum Relative to the Respective Advantages and Disadvantages of Various Forms of Compensation Law, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Draft of an Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: A Memorial Requesting the Recommendation of..., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Compliments of the Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and Their Prevention, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Memorandum against the adoption of the the so-called Elective Compensation Plan, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  February 20, 1917
  - Item 1: Draft Outline of a Model Safety Law, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and Their Prevention
    Notes: February 1, 1912
  - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Occupational Diseases, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Woman's Department of the National Civic Federation
    Notes: New York and New Jersey Section. April, 1914
  - Item 3: Tentative Draft: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Workmen's Compensation Department
    Notes: December 1, 1914
  - Item 4: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: January, 1915
  - Item 5: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Warren S. Stone; Timothy Healy
    Notes: February 20, 1917
  - Item 6: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Social Insurance Department
    Notes: January 15, 1917
  - Item 7: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: January 15, 1917. Second copy
  - Item 8: Executive Council of the National Civic Federation, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Warren S. Stone
    Notes: February 17, 1917. Circular letter
- Draft Outline of a Model Safety Law, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  February 1, 1912
  - Item 1: Draft Outline of a Model Safety Law, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Occupational Diseases, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Tentative Draft: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Executive Council of the National Civic Federation, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Report of the Committee on Occupational Diseases, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  New York and New Jersey Section. April, 1914
  - Item 1: Draft Outline of a Model Safety Law, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Occupational Diseases, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Tentative Draft: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Executive Council of the National Civic Federation, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  January, 1915
  - Item 1: Draft Outline of a Model Safety Law, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Occupational Diseases, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Tentative Draft: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Executive Council of the National Civic Federation, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  January 15, 1917
  - Item 1: Draft Outline of a Model Safety Law, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Occupational Diseases, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Tentative Draft: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Executive Council of the National Civic Federation, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  January 15, 1917. Second copy
  - Item 1: Draft Outline of a Model Safety Law, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Occupational Diseases, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Tentative Draft: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Executive Council of the National Civic Federation, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Executive Council of the National Civic Federation, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  February 17, 1917. Circular letter
  - Item 1: Draft Outline of a Model Safety Law, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Occupational Diseases, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Tentative Draft: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Executive Council of the National Civic Federation, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Tentative Draft: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  December 1, 1914
  - Item 1: Draft Outline of a Model Safety Law, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Occupational Diseases, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Tentative Draft: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Memorandum of Suggestions upon Main Provisions Requisite to an Adequate Compulsory Workmen's Compensation Law, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Compulsory Health Insurance, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Executive Council of the National Civic Federation, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Tentative Draft of An Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Second Report of the Committee on Foreign Inquiry, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: October 1, 1920
  - Item 2: Old Age Annuities: a Practical Guide for an Economically Sound Solution of the Pension Problem, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: Industrial Welfate Department
    Notes: July, 1925
  - Item 3: Supplementary Proposal: Old Age Annuities: Recommendations to Industrial Establishments for the Study and Formulation of Funded Pension Plans, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: December, 1926
  - Item 4: Preventable Accidents: a Tragic Page in American Industrial History (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: Flyer of news clippings with commentary
  - Item 5: Survey of Social and Industrial Conditions (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: Industrial Economics Department
  - Item 6: Tentative Draft of An Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: Legal Committee, Department on Compensation for Industrial Accidents and Their Prevention
- Second Report of the Committee on Foreign Inquiry, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  October 1, 1920
  - Item 1: Second Report of the Committee on Foreign Inquiry, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Old Age Annuities: a Practical Guide for an Economically Sound Solution of the Pension Problem, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Supplementary Proposal: Old Age Annuities: Recommendations to Industrial Establishments for the Study and Formulation of Funded Pension Plans, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Preventable Accidents: a Tragic Page in American Industrial History (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Survey of Social and Industrial Conditions (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Tentative Draft of An Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Old Age Annuities: a Practical Guide for an Economically Sound Solution of the Pension Problem, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  July, 1925
  - Item 1: Second Report of the Committee on Foreign Inquiry, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Old Age Annuities: a Practical Guide for an Economically Sound Solution of the Pension Problem, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Supplementary Proposal: Old Age Annuities: Recommendations to Industrial Establishments for the Study and Formulation of Funded Pension Plans, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Preventable Accidents: a Tragic Page in American Industrial History (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Survey of Social and Industrial Conditions (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Tentative Draft of An Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Supplementary Proposal: Old Age Annuities: Recommendations to Industrial Establishments for the Study and Formulation of Funded Pension Plans, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  December, 1926
  - Item 1: Second Report of the Committee on Foreign Inquiry, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Old Age Annuities: a Practical Guide for an Economically Sound Solution of the Pension Problem, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Supplementary Proposal: Old Age Annuities: Recommendations to Industrial Establishments for the Study and Formulation of Funded Pension Plans, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Preventable Accidents: a Tragic Page in American Industrial History (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Survey of Social and Industrial Conditions (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Tentative Draft of An Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Preventable Accidents: a Tragic Page in American Industrial History (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Flyer of news clippings with commentary
  - Item 1: Second Report of the Committee on Foreign Inquiry, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Old Age Annuities: a Practical Guide for an Economically Sound Solution of the Pension Problem, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Supplementary Proposal: Old Age Annuities: Recommendations to Industrial Establishments for the Study and Formulation of Funded Pension Plans, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Preventable Accidents: a Tragic Page in American Industrial History (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Survey of Social and Industrial Conditions (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Tentative Draft of An Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Survey of Social and Industrial Conditions (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Second Report of the Committee on Foreign Inquiry, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Old Age Annuities: a Practical Guide for an Economically Sound Solution of the Pension Problem, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Supplementary Proposal: Old Age Annuities: Recommendations to Industrial Establishments for the Study and Formulation of Funded Pension Plans, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Preventable Accidents: a Tragic Page in American Industrial History (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Survey of Social and Industrial Conditions (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Tentative Draft of An Act to Provide Compensation for Workmen Injured in Hazardous Industries (Box 1, Folder 3)